Guide to the Boehm Foundation (New York, N.Y.) Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Annual Grants, 1988-2004
  - Subseries 3.2: Annual Grants, 1988-2002
    - Democracy Now!--Pacifica Radio, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Democracy Resource Center, 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Development Gap, 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Foundation Center, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Gay, Lesbian and Straight Education Network (GLSEN), 1998 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Georgia Rural Urban Summit, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Globalvision/The Global Center, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Andrew Goodman Foundation, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Government Accountability Project (GAP), 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Grassroots International, 1997-1999 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Grassroots Leadership, 1998-2003 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Hague Appeal for Peace/World Federalist Movement, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Haiti Support Project, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Southern Studies, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Interhemispheric Resource Center, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission (IGLHRC), 1998 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - International Helping Hands, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - International Indian Treaty Council, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Jefferson Center, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Just Economics, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Kensington Welfare Rights Union, 1998-1999 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Lambi Fund of Haiti, 1997-2000 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Libraries for the Future, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Long Island Alliance for Peaceful Alternatives, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Montana Human Rights Network, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights (NNIRR), 1998 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - NGO Committee on Disarmament, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Nicaragua Network Education Fund, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Oxfam America, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Penn Center Sea Island Preservation Project, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Prisoners' Legal Services of New York, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Professionals' Network for Social Responsibility, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Public Interest Law Center of New Jersey, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Radio for Peace International, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Paul Robeson Fund for Independent Media, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Rural Organizing Project, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Shared Interest, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Southwest Network for Environmental and Economic Justice, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Symphony Space, 1996-1998 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - United for a Fair Economy, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Urban Justice Center, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - US + Cuba Medical Project (USCUMED), 1998 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Vermont International Film Festival, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1997-1999 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Workplace Project, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - World Federalist Association, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - YouthAction, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Africa Fund, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - American Jewish World Service/Comité de Emergencia Garífuna, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Bill of Rights Education Project, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Bread and Roses Cultural Project, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Center for Democratic Education, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Center for Democratic Renewal, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Center for Ethical Leadership--Soul of a Citizen, by Paul Rogat Loeb, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Center for New Community, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Coalition for Human Dignity, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Columbia Law School Program in Human and Civil Rights, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Commonwealth Education Project/Mass Votes for Clean Elections, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Community Resource Center, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Correctional Association of New York, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - CUNY Emergency Legal Defense Project, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Democracy Now!--Pacifica Radio, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Democracy Resource Center, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Disarm Education Fund--"Between Friends/Entre Amigos" Concert, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Foundation Center, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Fund for New Priorities in America--Global News Network, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Funding Exchange, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Georgia Rural Urban Summit, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Global Exchange, 1998-1999 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Government Accountability Project, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Grassroots International, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Highlander Research and Education Center, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission (IGLHRC), 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - International Indian Treaty Council, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Kensington Welfare Rights Union, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Labor Education & Research Project, 1998-1999 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Lambi Fund of Haiti, 1998-1999 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Long Island Alliance for Peaceful Alternatives, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - MADRE, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Minuteman Media, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Montana Human Rights Network, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Mother Jones, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - National Coalition of Education Activists (NCEA), 1999 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - National Interfaith Committee for Worker Justice, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - National Labor Committee in Support of Worker and Human Rights, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights/Center for Immigrant Rights, 1998-2000 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - National Network of Grantmakers, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Nicaragua-United States Friendship Office, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Peace Action, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Penn Center Land Use and Environmental Education Program, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - People's Rights Fund--Emergency Mobilization to Stop the War, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada (PLAN), 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Progressive Media Project, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Paul Robeson Fund for Independent Media, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Rural Organizing Project, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Shared Interest, 1998-2000 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Southeast Regional Economic Justice Network, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Maurice and Jane Sugar Law Center for Economic and Social Justice, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Symphony Space, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - UE Research & Education Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - U.S./Labor Education in the Americas Project, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Vermont International Film Foundation, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - WBAI--Pacifica Radio, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Workplace Project--Centro de Derechos Laborales, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - World Federalist Association, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - YouthAction, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN), 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Barbara Nimri Aziz, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Bread and Roses Cultural Project, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Center for Campus Organizing, 1999-2000 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Center for Economic Justice, 2000-2001 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Center for Ethical Leadership--Soul of a Citizen, by Paul Rogat Loeb (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Center for New Community, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Correctional Association of New York, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Critical Resistance East: Beyond the Prison Industrial Complex--Brecht Forum, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Culture Project--The Exonerated, by Jessica Blank and Erik Jensen, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Democracy Resource Center, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Downtown Residents for Community Empowerment, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Farm Labor Research Project, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Foundation Center, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Global Exchange, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Grassroots International, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Grassroots Leadership, 1999-2001 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Hague Appeal for Peace, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Charles Horman Truth Project, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Institute for Southern Studies, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Interhemispheric Resource Center, 1999-2001 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - International Indian Treaty Council, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization--John Brown Lives!, 1999-2000 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Labor Education & Research Project, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Lambi Fund of Haiti, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Long Island Alliance for Peaceful Alternatives, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Minuteman Media, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - National Coalition of Education Activists, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - National Interfaith Committee for Worker Justice, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - National Network of Grantmakers, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Peace Action Education Fund, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Leonard Peltier Defense Committee--Global Exchange, 2000-2001 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Leonard Peltier Defense Committee--Texas Civil Rights Project, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Progreso Latino--United Workers Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Progressive Media Project, 2000-2001 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Radio for Peace International, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Paul Robeson Fund for Independent Media, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Symphony Space, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - UE Research & Education Fund, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - United for a Fair Economy, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Urban Justice Center, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Vietnam Peace 25th Anniversary Committee--Brecht Forum, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - White Earth Land Recovery Project, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - World Federalist Association, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - YouthAction, 1998-2000 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Barbara Nimri Aziz, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Center for Third World Organizing, 2000-2001 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Correctional Association of New York, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Family Learning Project, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Foundation Center, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Grassroots International, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Prison Moratorium Project, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Progreso Latino--United Workers Committee, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Southeast Regional Economic Justice Network, 2001-2002 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Tides Foundation, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Workers Defense League, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Foundation Center, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Global Exchange, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Hague Appeal for Peace, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Progreso Latino--United Workers Committee, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Public Media, Inc., 2002 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3.3: New Leaders Grants, 2001-2004
    In January 2001, the Boehm Foundation changed its grant guidelines to focus its spending on two categories of multi-year grants: New Leaders Grants and Capacity Building Grants. As the brochure describing New Leaders Grants put it, they were designed to be "two-year general support grants ranging in size from $7,500 to $10,000 per year." New Leaders grants were intended to "support grassroots organizations that nurture progressive new activists and young leaders through work on specific public/private policy campaigns that address the Foundation's areas of concern." The material included in this subseries includes correspondence about the grant process, ranging from letters of inquiry to proposals to progress reports to published materials relating to the grantee organization's activities.
    The material in this subseries is arranged in alphabetical order according to the name of the grantee organization. Please note that any grantee organization named after a person takes the last name of the person for purposes of alphabetization. For example, "Maurice and Jane Sugar Law Center for Economic and Social Justice" is alphabetized under "S," for "Sugar."
    - Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Bill of Rights Education Project, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Center for Economic Justice, 2001-2003 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Center for New Community, 2001-2003 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Critical Resistance, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Grassroots Leadership, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - International Indian Treaty Council, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Jefferson Center for Education and Research, 2000-2002 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Kentucky Fairness Alliance, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Long Island Alliance for Peaceful Alternatives, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Maine Rural Workers Coalition, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights, 2003-2004 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Picture the Homeless, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada, 2002-2003 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Southwest Alliance to Resist Militarization (SWARM)/Peace Development Fund, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Maurice and Jane Sugar Law Center for Economic and Social Justice, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - White Earth Land Recovery Project, 2001-2003 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - United States Student Association Foundation, 2001-2004 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Youth Force Coalition, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3.4: Capacity Building Grants, 1999-2004
    Though officially launched in 2001 as the companion to the New Leaders program, Capacity Building Grants were given out by the Boehm Foundation on occasion before this period. As indicated in the Foundation's published guidelines from 2001, Capacity Building Grants were "two- or three-year grants ranging in size from $25,000 to $50,000 per year" and were "intended to help progressive organizations that are at a critical juncture in their development." Similar grants that were issued by the Boehm Foundation prior to 2001 may be found in Series II: Special Projects. As is the case in subseries 2 and 3, this subseries includes correspondence between the Boehm Foundation and the grantee organizations. However, due to the more substantial nature of the grants and the more rigorous application process, this subseries often contains more detailed applications and more extensive background information about the grantee organizations than the other subseries.
    The material in this subseries is arranged in alphabetical order according to the name of the grantee organization.
    - Africa Fund/Africa Action, 1999-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
    - Grassroots International, 2001-2004 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Highlander Research and Education Center, 2000-2004 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 2000-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
    - Institute for Southern Studies, 2001-2005 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Labor Education & Research Project, 2001-2003 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - National Coalition of Education Activists, 1999-2001 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2000-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - United for a Fair Economy, 2000-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
    - U.S./Labor Education in the Americas Project, 2001-2004 (Box 36, Folder f.5)